{C.H}

Web • C# • **Developer** 

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn • 07531 526 477

# **Background**

I am currently enjoying role at Modality Systems. I have worked on a variety of projects for a wide range of customers varying from Sainsbury's to Argonne National Laboratory.

I am extremely passionate about developing software. I take a huge amount of pride in my work and I am always looking into new technologies. My preferred language is C# although I also have experience with JavaScript and PHP.

# **Experience**

### **Applications Developer** Modality Systems

Feb 2015 - Present

During this role I initially worked on an existing product suite before then developing on both existing and brand new bespoke applications. This included a tool to aid consultants generate load on environments and also a project developing an API for Argonne National Laboratory. I have also been involved in various Microsoft TAP programs which were a great experience.

During my time at Modality Systems I've also learnt more about native windows development. I have worked on various Console and Windows Service applications. I've also been using the .NET futures API frequently. I have found working with other more experienced developers at Modality Systems extremely rewarding.

#### **Applications Developer** C A Design Services

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

This was my first development role. Upon starting the role I initially performed small support tasks and developed an in house web site to aid support for a particular product. During this time I also developed using Microsoft ASP.NET and C# for the first time since college. I then moved on to developing enhancements and bug fixes to older existing developments. These systems were usually 3-tier ASP.NET Web Form Applications with T-SQL databases.

As my role in the department grew I eventually began working on new developments and was the first person ever at the company to code a website using an ORM back end (Entity Framework) and also the MVC design pattern (ASP.NET MVC). My first project was for the large retail firm Sainsbury's. To deliver software to such a large firm in my first ever project, on my own, using new technologies, with no help or support, is something I am very proud of.

Despite almost all of my knowledge gained at C A Design Services being self-taught, I feel I have a learned a lot during my time there. This includes MVC, ORMs, C#, Dependency Injection, TDD and the SOLID principles.

# {C.H}

Connel Hooley

Web • C# • Developer

connelhooley.uk • me@connelhooley.uk • LinkedIn • 07531 526 477

## **Projects**

For further information on my personal projects please refer to my website

## **Skype For Business Load Generator**

Aug 2015 - Sept 2015

This tool is a console application that reads in an XML file and then places and answers Skype For Business calls using an API called UCMA. It makes heavy use of the .NET futures API to perform tasks concurrently.

### Sainsbury's Store Space®

Mar 2014 - Sept 2014

My responsibility in this project was to create a web application that interacted with data sent up to a server through an AutoCAD extension developed by a colleague. The website offered data viewing, reporting, panoramic photos, file storage and user management. It used technologies such as C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Ninject and jQuery.

#### **Handmade by Hooley**

Nov 2013

Handmade by Hooley is a personal project. It is simple WordPress theme. It was my first experience working with WordPress. During this project I experimented more with CSS than in any of my other previous projects up until this point.

<u>Lesson Planner</u> Aug 2013

Lesson Planner is a personal project that allows teachers to manage their lesson plans written in PHP. It uses the CakePHP framework to implement the MVC design pattern. Bootstrap is used for the front-end framework. This was my first experience using PHP with a framework and object relational mapping.

Qu	ап	TIC	аті	or.	1 C
<b>QU</b>	шп		шсі	$\mathbf{v}_{\mathbf{I}}$	

#### **BSc Hons in Software Engineering**

*University of East Anglia 2010 – 2013* 

2:2

#### **BTEC National Diploma in ICT**

Great Yarmouth College 2008 – 2010

**Triple distinction** 

**GCSEs** 

Cliff Park High School 2002 – 2006

Grade A: English Language Grade B: English Literature

Grade C: Science × 2, Maths, Statistics, ICT, Electronics, Art, PE, RE